A Guide to the Papers of Nancy Hale
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Nancy Hale
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3646 through 3646-f
This collection consists of ca. 750 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Nancy Hale Bowers: 3646, February 1, 1951; 3646-a, -b, February 28, 1951; 3646-c, June 21, 1954; 3646-d, April 13, 1955; 3646-e, December 30, 1955; 3646-f, December 20, 1956
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains a typescript and a galley proof for The sign of Jonah; letters and telegrams from Charles Scribner's Sons, Inc. and literary agent Elizabeth Nowall pertaining to the novel together with clipped reviews and three preliminary sketches for jacket illustrations.
The collection also contains manuscripts of short stories, articles, and poems; and manuscript notes and a partial draft for The Prodigal Women. Included is an untitled article about the University of Virginia Hospital with many stereotyped references to African Americans and mountain whites. Also of interest is a speech on the problems of the short story writer given at the University of Virginia Colonnade Club.
The collection also contains copies of some Elinor Wylie correspondence and reminiscences of her by Winifred Welles Shearer.
The collection also contains correspondence with publishers about financial arrangements and other matters, and fan letters from readers, chiefly regarding The Prodigal Women. Correspondents include Frank Crowninshield, Junius Fishburne, Arthur Krock, Dave Randall, Charles Wertenbaker and John Hall Wheelock. There is also a letter to Max Perkins from Evelyn Scott Metcalfe reviewing Hale's Never any more.
Miscellaneous items include a printed copy of Siva by her son William Wertenbaker, photographs from a production of a play and a review of The Prodigal Women by André Maurois.
Contents List
- The Sign of Jonah 1950, TMs, 517 pp. (Box 1)
  3646
- The Sign of Jonah 1950, galley proof, 140 sheets (Box 1)
- Among Oak, TMs fragment, ca. 65 pp. (Box 2)
  3646-e
- The Emperor's Ring, galley proof, ca. 100 sheets (Box 2)
- notes for The Prodigal Women, ca. 85 sheets (Box 2)
  3646-a
- The Sign of Jonah, notes and TmsS, ca. 300 sheets. (Box 2)
- The Sign of Jonah, notes and TmsS, ca. 200 sheets. (Box 2)
- Total Love, carbon TMs, 141 pp. (Box 2)
  3646-d
- The Young Die Good, TMs, 116 pp. (Box 2)
- The Hardpan Farm Series (Box 3)
  3646-f
- The Barn, 3 TmsS drafts, galley proofs ca. 24 pp. each (Box 3)
- The Beam, 3 TmsS drafts, 25 pp. each (Box 3)
- The Model, TMs, 28 pp. (Box 3)
- The Object, TMs, 26 pp. (Box 3)
- The Picture, notes, drafts, galleys, ca. 100 pp. (Box 3)
- fragments from The Hardpan Series, ca. 250 pp. (Box 3)
- The Barn and The Beam, notes and fragments, ca. 100 pp. (Box 3)
- The Actress We Each Are, AMs, 5 pp. (Box 4)
- After the Snow, TMs and carbon, 22 pp. and 25 pp. (Box 4)
- All He Ever Wanted, magazine pages, 6 sheets. (Box 4)
  3646-c
- All Things Lovely, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 4)
- Always Afternoon, magazine pages, 3 pp. (Box 4)
- The American Sisters, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 4)
- The American Sisters, carbon TMs, 10 pp. (Box 4)
- And In the Afternoon, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 4)
- Another World, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 4)
- Are Philosophers People?, TMs, 21 pp. (Box 4)
- Artificial Flowers, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 4)
- The Artist as an Old Bostonian, TMs, 20 pp. (Box 4)
- The Artist as an Old Bostonian, TMs, 25 pp. (Box 4)
- The Attractive Day, TMs, 24 pp. (Box 4)
- Back to Normal, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 4)
- Before the Mirror, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 4)
- Before the Train, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 4)
- Before the Train, carbon TMs, 12 pp. (Box 4)
- Between the Dark and the Daylight, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 4)
- Beyond the Alps Lies Italy, TMs, 22 pp. (Box 4)
- Beyond the Alps Lies Italy, TMs, 17 pp. (Box 4)
- Beyond the Alps Lies Italy, TMs, 22 pp. (Box 4)
- The Big Laugh, TMs, 2 versions 6 pp. (Box 4)
- The Blue Muslin Sepulcher, Scribner's Magazine, magazine pages, 3 sheets (Box 4)
- Book Review, Harper's Bazaar, magazine pages, 3 sheets (Box 4)
- Brahmin Beachead, Town and Country, magazine pages, 7 sheets (Box 4)
- The Break at Dawn, AMs, 12 pp. (Box 4)
- The Brook, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 4)
- The Brook, carbon TMs, 16 pp. (Box 4)
- The Bubble, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 4)
- The Carthaginian Rose, Ladies Home Journal, magazine pages, 5 sheets (Box 4)
- The Catalyst, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 4)
- A Change of Attire, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 4)
- A Change of Attire, TMs and 3 carbon TmsS, 15 pp. each (Box 4)
- Charlotte Russe, galley proof, 8 sheets (Box 4)
- Charlotte Russe, magazine page, 1 sheet (Box 4)
- A Child's World War, carbon TMs, 7 pp. (Box 4)
- A Child's World War, TMs, 7pp. (Box 4)
- A Child's World War, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 4)
- The China Sets, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 4)
- Christmas in the South, TMs, 16 pp. (Box 4)
- Christmas in the South, carbon TMs, 24 pp. (Box 4)
- The Citadel, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 4)
- Calloque Sentimentale, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 4)
- Colonel Zmizindorf, TMs, 41 pp. (Box 4)
- Crimson Autumn, TMs, 24 pp. (Box 4)
- Crimson Autumn, Redbook, magazine pages, 7 sheets (Box 4)
- The Crooks, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 4)
- The Crooks, carbon TMs, 9 pp. (Box 4)
- The Cruet, Tms, 7 pp. (Box 4)
- The Dark Mornings, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 5)
- The Dawn Patrol, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 5)
- The Dawn Patrol, carbon TMs, 12 pp. (Box 5)
- Dead March, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 5)
- Dead March, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 5)
- The Death of Mr. Walter's Heart, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 5)
- The Difference, TMs, 21 pp. (Box 5)
- The Dog-Light and the Cat-Light, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 5)
- The Dog-Light and the Cat-Light, carbon TMs, 13 pp. (Box 5)
- Dry-point of a Lady, magazine pages, 2 sheets (Box 5)
- The Earth Reborn, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 5)
- Eastern Point, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 5)
- Eastern Point, carbon TMs, 9 pp. (Box 5)
- Emotions by God, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 5)
- The Empress's Ring, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 5)
- Entrance into Life, magazine pages, 2 sheets (Box 5)
- Examples, TMs, 12 sheets (Box 4)
- The Fair, carbon TMs, 16 pp. (Box 4)
- Family Ties, TMs, 17 pp. (Box 5)
- Family Ties, carbon TMs, 20 pp. (Box 5)
- Fear, carbon TMs, 5 pp. (Box 5)
- Fear, magazine pages, 2 sheets. (Box 5)
- The First Haircut, TMs, 16 pp. (Box 5)
- The First One, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 5)
- The Flight Abroad, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 5)
- For Art's Sake, The New Yorker, magazine pages, 2 sheets (Box 5)
- The Fox, TMs, 18 pp. (Box 5)
- The Fox, TMs, 18 pp. (Box 5)
- The Fox, carbon TMs, 18 pp. (Box 5)
- Funny Woman, Frank Crowninshield to Mra. Nancy Hardin (Nancy Hale) 1934 February 1, TMs, 3 pp. with TLS (Box 5)
- The General's Daughter (Box TMs, 9 pp.)
- The Girl in my Arms, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 5)
- When Nobody Came, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 5)
- The Gods Kill Some Time, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 5)
- Hallowe'en, carbon TMs, 7 pp. (Box 5)
- The Haunted Woman, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 5)
- The Haunted Woman, carbon TMs, 4 pp. (Box 5)
- The Haunted Woman, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 5)
- A Haunting, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 5)
- A Haunting, galley proof (Box 5)
- How Would you Like to be Born, TMs, 14 pp. (Box 5)
- How Would You Like to be Born, carbon TMs, 14 pp. (Box 5)
- Hurricane-Jacks, TMs, 18 pp. (Box 5)
- In Place of Calling, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 5)
- Inside, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 5)
- Inside, carbon TMs, 6 pp. (Box 5)
- The Insult, TMs, 8 pp. (Folder 5)
- An Introduction to the Glamour, notes, drafts, fragments, ca. 35 sheets (Box 5)
- It Really Is, TMs, 22 pp. (Box 5)
- It Really Is, TMs, 17 pp. (Box 5)
- Janey's Atom, carbon TMs, 14 pp. (Box 5)
- The King of Fancy's Daughter, TMs, drafts, fragments, ca. 35 sheets (Box 5)
- Last Summer, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 5)
- The Last Time, magazine pages, 2 sheets. (Box 5)
- The Last Time, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 5)
- The Leap, carbon TMs (first version), 9 pp. (Box 5)
- The Leap, TMs (revision), 10 pp. (Box 5)
- The Leap, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 5)
- A Letter Home, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 5)
- A Letter to My Love, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 5)
- The Little Baron, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 5)
- Little Family, TMs, 11pp. (Box 5)
- The Lost Love, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 5)
- The Lost Love, magazine pages, 2 sheets (Box 5)
- Love, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 5)
- Love, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 5)
- Luke, TMs, 27 pp. (Box 5)
- The Mahogany Box, TMs, 20 pp. (Box 6)
- The Mahogany Box, TMs, ca. 20 pp. (Box 6)
- Make Friends With Your Family, TMs, ca. 12 pp. (Box 6)
- Make Friends With Your Family, carbon TMs, 10 pp. (Box 6)
- Man Stands in Need, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 6)
- Misericordia, carbon TMs, 21 pp. (Box 6)
- Miss August, TMs, ca. 20 pp. (Box 6)
- Miss Smith From Jackson City, TMs, 25 pp. (Box 6)
- The Misses Harris, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 6)
- Monster, magazine pages, 4 sheets (Box 6)
- Mortality, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 6)
- Mother, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 6)
- Mother, carbon TMs, 12 pp. (Box 6)
- Mr. Britton, New Yorker, magazine pages, 2 sheets (Box 6)
- Mr. McPharlane, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 6)
- Mr. Robbin, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 6)
- Mr. Robbin, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 6)
- Mrs. Stanislas: by Sargent, AMs, 6 pp. (Box 6)
- Music Without Words, TMs,ca. 27 pp. (Box 6)
- Music Without Words, Collier's, magazine pages, 4 sheets. (Box 6)
- My Sister Kate, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 6)
- The Narrow Sense of the Word, TMs, several drafts and fragments, ca. 40 pp. (Box 6)
- A New Day, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 6)
- New England in Her Bones, carbon TMs, 10 pp. (Box 6)
- A New Life, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 6)
- The New Order, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 6)
- No Accounting for Taste, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 6)
- No Other Gods, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 6)
- No Work for Ladies, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 6)
- Not Soloman, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 6)
- Not Soloman, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 6)
  3646-e With TLS 5 Oct. 1948 Henry Volkening to Mrs. Bowers and TLS 1 Oct. 1948 Gus to Henry Volkening
- O Mason All to Thee, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 6)
- O Mason All to Thee, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 6)
  3646-e With TLS 17 June 1938 Bruce Gould to Miss Elizabeth Nowell and TLS 20 June 1938 Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale.
- Object of Virtue, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 6)
- Odd Fellows' Hall, Scribner's, magazine pages, 2 sheets (Box 6)
- Of Giving Many Dinners, TMs, 14 pp. (Box 6)
  3646-d With 6 pp. of AMs notes.
- Old Stuff, TMs, 26 pp. (Box 6)
- On The Beach, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 6)
- On The Beach, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 6)
- On The Beach, carbon TMs, 13 pp. (Box 6)
- One Good Dress, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 6)
- One Touch of Malice, TMs, 15 pp. (Box 6)
- Open Sesame, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 6)
- Order, TMs, 19 pp. (Box 6)
- The Other Road Spring 1956, folcio vol. xxi, no. 2 (Box 6)
- Outside, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 6)
- Overnight, TMs, 19 pp. (Box 7)
- Overnight, Collier's, magazine pages, 2 sheets. (Box 7)
- A Party of Four, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 7)
- Persephone, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 7)
- The Petals of the Flower, carbon TMs, 9 pp. (Box 7)
- The Place and the Time, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 7)
- The Place and Wherever You Are, carbon TMs, 13 pp. (Box 7)
- The Poet, TMs, 18 pp. (Box 7)
- The Princess, TMs, 41 pp. (Box 7)
- The Readville Stars, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 7)
- The Readville Stars, magazin pages, 1 sheet (Box 7)
- The Reality, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 7)
- The Reality, carbon TMs, 10 pp. (Box 7)
- Recovery, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 7)
- Recovery, carbon TMs, 12 pp. (Box 7)
- Room for a Baby, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 7)
- Room for a Baby, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 7)
  3646-e With TLS 28 July 1938 Elizabeth Nowell to Charles Wertenbaker and TLS 28 July 1938 Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale and TLS 11 July 1938 V. Vetluquin to Elizabeth Nowell.
- Rosie and Jinny and Jim, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 7)
- The Rusted House, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 7)
- The Rusted House, carbon TMs, 7 pp. (Box 7)
- The Secret Garden, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 7)
- The Seed of Destruction, TMs, 51 pp. (Box 7)
- Self-Made Cinderella, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 7)
- Separation, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 7)
- She Never Saw The Circus, magazine pages, 2 sheets (Box 7)
- The Sheltered One, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 7)
- A Short Story, TMs, 21 pp. (Box 7)
- Silver-Spoon Trouble, TMs, 19 pp. (Box 7)
- The Sisters, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 7)
- The Sisters, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 7)
- The Sisters, carbon TMs, 11 pp. (Box 7)
- The Skeptical Shepherd, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 7)
- The Slave, TMs, 22 pp. (Box 7)
- The Slave, TMs, 19 pp. (Box 7)
- A Slow Boat to China, TMs--notes, drafts, fragments, ca. 40 pp. (Box 7)
  3646-e With TLS 29 June 1955 J.C. Wyllie to Fredson Bowers.
- A Slow Boat to China, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 7)
- The Snows of Childhood, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 7)
- The Snows of Childhood, carbon TMs, 11 pp. (Box 7)
- The Snows of Childhood, The New Yorker, magazine pages, 3 sheets, 2 copies (Box 7)
- Some Day I'll Find You, carbon TMs, 17 pp. (Box 7)
- Souvenir of Dr. Grady, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 7)
- The Story of Jean Strecker, TMs, 18 pp. (Box 7)
- The Story of Jean Strecker, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 7)
- The Strange Case of Mr. Biddle, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 7)
- The Strange Case of Mr. Biddle, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 7)
- The Stranger Venus, carbon TMs, 64 pp. (Box 7)
- The Stranger Venus, Redbook's Novelette of the Month, magazine pages, 9 sheets (Box 7)
- A Summer's Long Dream, TMs, 20 pp. (Box 7)
  3646-e With 6 sheets of autograph notes.
- Summertime, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 8)
- The Taming of Miss Shrewsbury, 2 carbon TmsS, 17 pp. (Box 8)
- Tampering with Mr. Wodehouse, TMs, 2 pp. (Box 8)
- That Woman, TMs, 23 pp. (Box 8)
- Though It Breaks My Heart to Go, magazine page, 1 sheet (Box 8)
- The Tide, TMs, 5 sheets, 1 sheet AMs notes (Box 8)
- To Kill a Cat, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 8)
- To Kill a Cat, cabon TMs, 8 pp. (Box 8)
- To The Invader, TMs, fragment 4 pp. (Box 8)
- To Those Who Sit in Darkness, carbon TMs, 20 pp. (Box 8)
- To Those Who Sit in Darkness, TMs, 17 pp. (Box 8)
- The Toast of New York, TMs, 4 pp. with two sheets of AMs notes (Box 8)
- Too Many Doctors, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 8)
  3646-c with TLS Allene Talley (for Vogue ) to Mrs. Charles Wertenbaker (Nancy Hale)
- The Ultimate Valentine, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 8)
- Violation, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 8)
- Violet, TMs, 14 pp. (Box 8)
- The Wages of Whoopee, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 8)
- The Warm Coat, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 8)
- The Warm Coat, carbon TMs, 6 pp. (Box 8)
- The Waxen Man, The American Mercury, magazine pages, 3 sheets (Box 8)
- The Way of Dreams, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 8)
- Weeping Alexanders, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 8)
- Where is My Father, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 8)
- White Poppies Die; The Wedding Present, TMs, 10 pp.; TMs, 5 pp. (Box 8)
  3646-c With TLS Adèle Ballot to Mrs. Nancy Hardin (Nancy Hale).
- Wild Boy of Carl Schurtz Park, TMs, 2 pp. (Box 8)
- The Wings, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 8)
- With Brief Thanksgiving, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 8)
- A Yankee's Disillusionment, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 8)
- A Yankee's Disillusionment, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 8)
- The Year I Had the Colds, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 8)
- Young Lochinvar and the Tragic Muse, TMs, 15 pp. (Box 8)
- You Can't Run Away, Ladies Home Journal, magazine pages, 5 sheets (Box 8)
- The Young Girl, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 8)
- The Young Girl, 2 carbon TmsS, 15 pp. each (Box 8)
- Young Man of Affairs, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 8)
- Panama a description of, TMs, 3 sheets (Box 8)
- untitled article about Julie Rayburn, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 8)
- untitled article about Kent, Massachusetts, TMs, 5 sheets. (Box 8)
- untitled story about Felicia, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 8)
- untitled story about newly wed couple, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 8)
- untitled story about being in love, 17, and in New York for 3 days at Christmas, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 8)
- untitled story about Clarissa Drew, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 8)
- untitled story about University Hospital, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 8)
- untitled story, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 8)
- 17 untitled short stories and articles, TmsS, ca. 120 pp. (Box 8)
- story notes, AMS, ca. 30 pp. (Box 8)
- The Church for Me, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 9)
- The Church for Me, carbon TMs, 10 pp. (Box 9)
- The Discomforts of Home, TMs with extensive autograph corrections, 9 pp. (Box 9)
- Ever Let the Fancy, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 9)
- Ever Let the Fancy, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 9)
- Ever Let the Fancy, galley proof, 7 sheets (Box 9)
  3646-f with TLS William to Nancy
- How to Keep Going Through Wretched, TMs, 10 pp. (with carbon copy of first two pages) (Box 9)
- How to Keep Going Through Wretched, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 9)
  3646-e With TLS Ethel Kraimer (secretary to Miss Nowell) to Miss Hale.
- Letter to a Young Writer, from Richmond Times Dispatch, 3 pp. with published letter (Box 9)
- Little Lord Who-Am-I, review of Little Lord Fauntleroy by Francis Hodgson Burnett (for the Georgia Review), TMs, 7 pp. (Box 9)
- Painted Into a U-Corner, TMs, 15 sheets with extensive autograph corrections (Box 9)
- Pierce's, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 9)
- Pierce's, galley proof, 6 sheets (Box 9)
- To Elinor Wylie, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 9)
- What God was Writing, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 9)
- What Makes a Memory Unforgettable, various versions, TMs, 33 sheets (Box 9)
- untitled about University Hospital, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 9)
- an address on creative writing, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 9)
- an address on the problems of the short story writer delivered at the Colonnade Club, TMs (Box 9)
- miscellaneous sheets of plots, fragments, etc., TMs and AMs, ca. 15 pp. (Box 9)
- newspaper clippings related to Nancy Hale and her work, ca. 20 items (Box 9)
- miscellaneous sheets from The New Yorker, 8 items (Box 9)
- advertising magazine of J.P. Toth Verlag, Hamburg, with front cover picture of Nancy Hale., 7 copies (Box 9)
- miscellaneous papers of Nancy Hale (small notebook, old photographs and negatives, royalty reports, 2 copyright forms) (Box 9)
- miscellaneous story notes, fragments, and plot outlines., TMs and AMs, ca. 200 sheets. (Box 9)
- story notes, plot outlines, all AMs, ca. 50 sheets (Box 9)
- miscellaneous notes and fragments, TMs and AMs, ca. 40 sheets (Box 9)
- A New Novel, TMs, ca. 20 sheets (Box 9)
- Somewhere She Dances, TMs with extensive autograph corrections and notes, ca. 80 pp. (Box 10)
- The Collaborators, TMs, ca. 80 pp. (Box 10)
  3646-c With ca. 50 sheets of autograph notes and miscellaneous notes and magazine pages of Shall We Pan the Ladies by Wolcott Jibbs
- material for a play, TMs and AMs, ca. 80 pp. (Box 10)
- poems, TMs and AMs, 7 sheets (Box 10)
- poems, TMs and AMs, ca. 100 sheets (Box 10)
- pencil sketches of nudes, a girl's face, 6 items (Box 10)
- advertising copy, TMs, ca. 20 pp. (Box 10)
- scrapbooks of material written for Vogue, 4 items (Box 10)
- What Interests Women and Why, 2 copies of printed article (Box 10)
- pamphlet put of by Cowan and Dengler about Nancy Hale as an advertising copy writer., 1 item (Box 10)
- Elinor Wylie correspondence (Elinor Wylie letter and letters to Nancy Hale about these letters), TmsS, 20 letters (Box 10)
- reminiscences of Elinor Wylie by Winifred Welles Shearer, TMs, 19 pp. (Box 10)
  3646-e With ALS Winifred Welles Shearer to Nancy Hale 12 November 1937.
- Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale 1938, 8 TLS (Box 11)
- Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale 1947, 1 ALS (Box 11)
- Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale 1949, 14 TLS (Box 11)
- Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale 1950, 40 TLS (Box 11)
- Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale 1951, 29 TLS (Box 11)
- Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale 1952, 27 TLS (Box 11)
- Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale 1953-1954, 38 TLS and ALS (Box 11)
- Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale 1955-1956, 63 TLS and ALS (Box 11)
- Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale n.d., 11 TLS and ALS (Box 11)
- letters from The New Yorker, mainly William Maxwell to Nancy Hale 1933-1956, 69 TLS and ALS (Box 11)
- letters from Charles Scribner's Sons, mainly from Charles Auburn and John Hall Wheelock 1942-1950, 33 TLS and ALS (Box 11)
- letters from Charles Scribner's Sons, mainly from John Hale Wheelock 1950-1956, 49 TLS and ALS (Box 11)
- miscellaneous correspondence 1931-1954, 31 TLS and ALS (Box 12)
- miscellaneous correspondence 1955-1956, 63 TLS and ALS (Box 12)
- miscellaneous correspondence n.d., 5 ALS (Box 12)
- newspaper clippings, advertising brochures, magazine clippings (Box 12)
- Virginia engagements calendar used by Nancy Hale 1951 (Box 12)
- Daily Reminder Calendar used by Nancy Hale 1952 (Box 12)
- notebooks n.d., 3 items (Box 12)
- newspaper reviews of The Empress's Ring1955 (Box 12)
- review of Femmes Prodigues by Andre Maurois de L'Academie Francaise, in French. n.d. (Box 12)
- miscellaneous newspaper clippings n.d. (Box 12)
- reprints of a biographical sketch of Nancy Hale written by Henry Hart for The Boston Evening Transcript2 April 1932, 16 reprints (Box 12)
- miscellaneous vouchers, correspondence, photographs n.d. (Box 12)
  3646-b
- Book-of-the-Month Club advertising circular for The Sign of Jonahn.d., 5 copies (Box 12)